defensereview.com 2002-08-21

# Defense Review

Defense Review Network Privacy Policy

Welcome to the Defense Review Network, owned and produced by Defense Review, Inc. and its subsidiary and affiliate corporations, successors, and assigns (collectively referred to as "Defense Review"). The "Defense Review Network," which may expand or change from time to time, are made available subject to this Privacy Policy. This statement discloses the privacy practices of the Defense Review Network. By using the Products and Services, you agree, without limitation or qualification, to be bound by this Privacy Policy or any other privacy or data collection policy applicable to any individual Defense Review Network web site. 

This policy may be updated from time to time so please check back periodically. 

1\. What information of yours does the Defense Review Network collect?

The goal of the Defense Review Network is to be your favorite destination on the Internet by providing you with the information, services and product offerings that are most relevant to you. To achieve this goal, the Defense Review Network needs to collect information to understand what differentiates you from its millions of other unique users. We collect two types of information from you, "anonymous information" and "personally identifiable information." Anonymous information refers to information that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. Each time a visitor comes to a Defense Review Network site, Defense Review collects some information to improve the overall quality of the visitor's online experience. Defense Review collects the visitor's IP address (e.g., whether the user is logged on from a .com, .gov or .edu domain), referral data (e.g., the address of the last URL a user visited prior to clicking through to a Defense Review Network site), and browser and platform type (e.g., a Netscape browser on a Macintosh platform). Defense Review also collects aggregate search terms from search services for internal reporting and targeted advertising. Defense Review collects this user information for purposes of product monitoring, product improvement, and targeted advertising. 

In addition to this anonymous data, Defense Review may also collect personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information refers to information that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name and postal address. Wherever and whenever Defense Review collects personal information through registration we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. If you contact the Defense Review Network, we may keep a record of that correspondence. We do not collect any e-mail addresses of those who communicate with the Defense Review Network via e-mail. We use the information provided so that we may respond to the e-mail. 

2\. What are "cookies" and how does Defense Review use them?

In addition to the personally identifiable information that Defense Review collects, we also collect information "anonymously" using "cookies." Presently, "cookies" play an important role in making the Internet work, but there is much confusion among Internet users about what cookies are and how they are used. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a web site to the hard drive of your computer so that the web site may identify you and track your activities on the web site. This unique number identifies your browser-- but not you -- to Defense Review computers whenever you visit one of the sites in the Defense Review Network. A cookie will not let a web site know any personally identifiable information about you, such as your real name and address. Defense Review is not generally interested in any one individual and does not collect personally identifiable information about any one person using cookies. The coding in the cookies Defense Review sets lets us know that you are using a particular computer but nothing more. Since cookies are only text files, they cannot run on your computer, search your computer for other information or transmit any information to anyone.

To help serve you better Defense Review generally uses cookies to:

Help us remember who you are through your browser settings so that Defense Review can offer and provide personalized services.  Defense Review uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about whom has done and seen what across our Network of sites. Cookies also allow us to save passwords and preferences for you so that you will not have to re-enter them the next time you visit. Help merchants in Defense Review Shop track business at their stores and process orders in individual shopping carts; Measure traffic patterns. Without cookies, it could be difficult for Defense Review to know that certain services are more popular than others are. This information helps us to better understand when to open up new services.  Estimate audience size. Cookies help us know whether or not users have seen particular displays, including advertising, so we do not bore you with the same material over and over again. Displaying advertisements. Third party advertising networks for Defense Review may issue cookies when serving advertisements.

The use of cookies is now an industry standard, and you will find them used on most major web sites. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser either to notify you when you have received a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies. You should understand that while Defense Review does not require you to use cookies, however certain sites will not function properly if you set your browser to not accept cookies. 

3\. What organization is collecting the information? 

When you register information in any Internet domain of the Defense Review Network, that information is generally collected and maintained solely by the Defense Review Network unless specifically stated otherwise at the point of collection. If data is collected and/or maintained by any company other than the Defense Review Network, we will tell you at the point of collection. If you do not want to share your information with that company, you can choose not to use that service. Please see the Section entitled "With whom does the Defense Review Network share information that is collected?" for a more complete list of companies that Defense Review works with to provide you Products and Services.

Defense Review runs many promotions and sweepstakes across its Network. These promotions may be sponsored or co-sponsored by third parties. Data collected during a promotion is typically shared with the sponsor or co-sponsor. Defense Review will inform you at the point of collection whether or not we are sharing your personal data as a result of your participation in a promotion or sweepstakes. If you do not want to have the Defense Review Network share your data, you can choose not to participate in the promotion or sweepstakes.

Be aware that Defense Review Network sponsors and other advertisers have links on our sites that take you to other sites that may collect personally identifiable information about you. Defense Review hopes that all third parties involved adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our users. However, this Defense Review Network Privacy Policy does not cover third party data collection practices and the Defense Review Network does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties. 

4\. How does the Defense Review Network use the information it collects? 

Any personal information you provide to Defense Review when registering for Products and Services at any of its Network sites is maintained and accessible only by the Defense Review Network unless specifically stated otherwise. Defense Review requests information from its users so that users can enjoy customized experiences across the Defense Review Network, including personalization services, interactive communications, games, online shopping and many other types of content and services. Most of these Products and Services are free to you. In order to provide great content and services free of charge, Defense Review displays advertisements.

For instance, if you told the Defense Review Network that you were interested in receiving offers or information from selected Defense Review Network sponsors and advertisers, Defense Review will send you email about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. For those who elect to receive such materials from Defense Review or third parties, and who indicate that they do in their profile, Defense Review will release personally identifiable information. Information released includes name, e-mail address and other information supplied in the Defense Review Network registration process. The Defense Review Network sometimes uses an individual registered user’s data to "pre-populate" forms that are displayed for the purpose of collecting individual data by the Defense Review Network and/or its advertisers and sponsors. If you enter a sweepstakes or a contest on the Defense Review Network, we will use the information you provided to contact you in the event you win.  Defense Review may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide information on individual users to the appropriate governmental authorities.

5\. With whom does the Defense Review Network share the information that is collected? 

In order to provide you with content and services that match your interests, the Defense Review Network has relationships with many of the best services and content companies. Many of these services also require registration to make them function properly. You can recognize most of these sites by the joint branding of Defense Review and such companies. You should make every effort to read the individual privacy policies of the partners, and make an informed decision on your own whether or not to continue based upon these sites' privacy practices and your own discretion. You may opt-out of sharing your information with such partners by choosing not to use that service or content. 

You will find direct links on our site to sites offered by third parties. Some of these sites are authorized to use the Defense Review Network brands and/or logos. No third party sites are covered by this privacy policy. If you feel that a site using a Defense Review Network brand and/or logo does not follow an acceptable privacy policy, please contact the Defense Review. 

6\. How can you access, edit or delete your information? 

The Defense Review Network provides its registered users the ability to access and edit the personal information in their user profiles. Currently, to access and edit your personal information, you have to go to the specific Defense Review Network site where you registered. 

7\. What is the opt-out policy for the Defense Review Network?

The Defense Review Network offers you the ability to opt-out of receiving information on Defense Review Network updates and new services, as well as direct mail offers from selected Defense Review Network partners and sponsors. This is done at the point of initial collection of information and during the editing or updating process. The instructions to opt out of most Defense Review Network email newsletters and direct mail communications are the same as the instructions listed above for editing user information profiles. In addition, all Defense Review Network newsletters and direct email communications have easy-to-follow unsubscribe instructions at the bottom.

8\. What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information? 

The Defense Review Network has security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. Only authorized employees have access to the information you provide us with.  While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we make every effort to prevent such unfortunate occurrences. Any other particularly sensitive information, such as your credit card number collected for a commerce transaction at Defense Review Shop or to purchase premium services, is encrypted prior to transmission. 

You are ultimately responsible for the security of your Defense Review Network ID and password. Please take care when using and storing them. Defense Review recommends that you do not divulge your password to anyone. You should log out of your browser at the end of each computer session to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence, especially if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.

9\. The Defense Review Network notice regarding the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)? 

The Defense Review Network, in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) of 1998, provides notice to parents of children under 13 that: 

The Defense Review Network may collect personal information from children under 13 years of age in order to provide them with access to services and content on the Defense Review Network; The Defense Review Network needs the consent of parents or guardians to collect, use and disclose personally identifiable information about children under 13; The Defense Review Network has created a mechanism by which parents and guardians can provide consent; The Defense Review Network may not require children under 13 to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of participation; The Defense Review Network has created a mechanism by which parents or guardians can, upon verification, review their children’s personal information, ask to have that information deleted, and refuse to allow any further collection or use of their children’s personal information.

The Defense Review Network encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered on the sites that they visit. No information should be submitted to or posted at the Defense Review Network by visitors and registered users under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian.

The Defense Review Network does not knowingly permit children under the age of 13 to register without the verifiable consent of their parents or guardians. 

10\. What you can do to better protect yourself on the Internet?

Know the risks.  When you communicate with others online, you should be aware that, when disclosing personal information such as one's actual name, member name, e-mail address, etc., on a web page, in a newsgroup, chat room or forum, that information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties, outside the Defense Review Network. Some of the e-mail you receive may be useful to you, but some may not.  In an effort to curtail unsolicited e-mail, Defense Review blocks certain e-mail addresses and domains from sending e-mail communications to e-mail addresses at our domains. 

Educate yourself.  Search the Web for as much information as you can about how to protect your privacy. Look for a privacy statement in the sites you visit. A good place to start is TRUSTe -- an independent, non-profit privacy initiative dedicated to building users' trust and confidence in the Internet. Please visit the Federal Trade Commission’s web site and read information on being an informed Internet Traveler and other privacy initiatives. Additional privacy resources can be found at by clicking on any of the following links: 

     The Privacy Rights Clearinghouse

     http://www.privacyrights.org/ 

     Center for Democracy and Technology

     http://www.cdt.org/privacy/ - Data Privacy

     http://www.cdt.org/privacy/guide/ - Guide to Online Privacy 

     Direct Marketing Association (DMA)

     http://www.the-dma.org/ 

     Electronic Frontier Foundation - non-profit dedicated to

     protecting public interest in online privacy. http://www.eff.org 

     EPIC.org (Electronic Privacy Information Center) 

     http://www.epic.org 

     Georgetown Internet Privacy Study

     http://www.msb.edu/faculty/culnanm/gippshome.html 

     NetCoalition.com

     http://www.netcoalition.com 

     Network Advertising Initiative

     http://www.networkadvertising.org/ 

     Online Privacy Alliance

     http://www.privacyalliance.org/ 

Tell your children: "Never talk to strangers!"  While the Defense Review Network works hard to protect children on its sites, Defense Review cannot protect their privacy once they leave. Please teach children to not give out their names or other personal information to anyone on the Internet. They should also be instructed not to fill out any forms or register at any website without your knowledge and consent. Take advantage of the online resources for parents available on the Defense Review Network, such as SearchGuard and GetNetWise.

Use PGP (Pretty Good Privacy) http://www.pgp.com or another encryption program.

 Copyright © 2000 Defense Review, Inc. Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions Standard Advertising Terms and Conditions
